[Music]
right so this has to be
true if e star is truly a fixed point
right some something so V Star is truly
a fixed point then this will be zero so
otherwise it will be something greater
than zero right so because of the fact
of this being a
Norm's no for huh no for there's no case
for less than zero so this is fine right
all of this is the thing so now what
we'll do is we'll use our
friend the triangle inequality again
like I said it's very simple proof right
all we are doing is just using the
triangle inequality again and again
right so use a triangle inequality again
so what we
get
is
so what do we know we know that VN
kosi so we know that VN is
kosi so this sequence is going
to this this this this thing right V
Star minus VN minus one is going
to go to
zero right I mean that is by definition
of c sequence V Star minus VN minus one
will go to zero likewise VN minus V Star
will also go to Zero by virtue of the
fact that VN is
CI that is the definition we had earlier
right so that it's going to converge
right
so it will go to zero no no no no V Star
is
the converion point right so we know
that V Star because of it being banak we
know that V Star exists in
you right so that's the thing we had
right limit as n TS to Infinity
VN will go to V Star that's what we mean
by saying it's
convergent right limit as n tends to
Infinity VN is going to V Star so limit
as n tends to Infinity V Star minus VN
will go to
zero limit as n tends to Infinity that's
the crucial Point here right you're
going to be doing this
forever and if the difference is going
to be something small when it goes
forever that means it's not convergent
Pro that's assumption we have made see
what I am trying to prove is
that what I'm trying to prove is that T
V Star equal to V Star is a fixed
point right that V Star is a fixed point
of T is what I'm trying to prove right
the fact that VN is
CI right tells me that if I apply T
infinitely often enough I'll anyway
conver to V Star
[Music]
anyway reach V Star what I'm trying to
show is once you reach V Star you don't
go anywhere you just stop there under
T that makes sense so the the sequence
I'm generating VN VN plus 1 VN plus 2
and so on so forth I'm showing that it
is
Kashi right so that means if I apply T
infinitely often enough I'll eventually
reach infinitely often yeah infinite
should be enough uh so if I apply T
infinitely often I'll reach
V Star so that process is there what we
are trying to show is okay V Star is
actually a fixed Point once you reach V
Star you're going
nowhere we could have just put m = 1 and
N = to and taken the limit n TS to
Infinity for that the previous one we
yeah that one what would you have gotten
PL in m = 1 and then mending to Infinity
Tak on the limit yeah what would have
got RS becomes zero okay and then so
you'll show that it is the successive
differen has become
zero but then that just b n plus one is
can be written as T
TVN so TVN minus VN will be less than
equal to Z yeah so essentially you'll
show that as it tends to Infinity it
will become zero it become Z it'll
become zero but you have to show that V
Star if it reaches V Star it stop there
that's all we are showing here when it
reaches V it won't go anywhere Beyond V
Star that's it
right so we just showing that it will
stop at V Star that's basically what we
are trying to show here and uh uh
since
okay this is
Trivial
okay in fact we can actually show it
that way also okay as limit and tends to
Infinity
uh okay now the
uniqueness
from the contraction property so uar and
V Star are two different fix points for
T from the contraction property we have
t star Minus TV star should be less than
or equal to Lambda * ustar minus V Star
Norm of ustar minus V Star but since
they are fixed points the right left
hand side is also ustar minus V Star so
I'm asking you for ustar minus V Star
should be less than or Al to Lambda *
uar minus V
Star for Lambda non zero Lambda that is
satisfied only
for only if V Star equal to ustar oh
sorry
no if Lambda is not one then it
satisfied
for yeah so even if Lambda is zero it
has to be that uar equal to V
Star
doesn't matter right I me we just using
the contraction property just this this
is sufficient to show that ustar has to
be equal to V
Star right so as long as Lambda is not
one and anyway we have excluded Lambda 1
here right so as long as Lambda is not
equal to one so this implies
that
great so what we have done so far is
shown the the B fix theorem is
correct right we need to show
that L LP is a contraction so if you
show LP is a contraction you get
everything else for
free
right so we need to show Alp is a
contraction so let's do that and I'll
stop after
that
[Music]
SP
yeah
ah why don't people stop
me
okay what I do V minus u v minus U
sorry okay so far just
algebra okay so now what I going to say
is well I don't care what J I'm
considering the confusion of the
notation so uh u and v are vectors but
ufs and VFS are scalers ufs and VFS are
yeah sing but all the contraction
mapping results are for Vector Norms
right so mean all all the contraction
mapping results are so far for Vector
Norms yeah so do we element twise do
they correspond to that I mean the
maximum of that particular Vector has to
be lesser than the maximum of another
vector
but each element wise they need not be
lesser uh element wise they need not
be lesser no that's not needed
yeah only the max nor wise yeah the max
of this should be less
than that expression is again for a
scalar expression whatever I'm writing
so far is a scalar expression okay I'll
come to the vector form of this okay so
far I'm writing scal
yeah so
now so the tricky thing now I'm going to
say see I'm summing over all J right so
I'm going to look at this expression so
what I'm going to say is this
expression right will always be bounded
by vus
U right the max
now
right so this is a pretty loose Bond
right so I'm taking each element here
I'm looking at this right each element
of this will be bounded at most by the
max nor right so it can't be any greater
than the max Norm difference therefore
I'll say that this expression is lesser
than or equal to gamma * the max Norm
into that right so that anyway goes to
zero so this is essentially equal
to
okay so at every point this will satisfy
that okay this is one
way so go to the other
way then you can do the other way easily
enough right you'll end up with the same
thing nor of vus U is the same of Norm
of uus V so you'll end up with the same
expression right so essentially I can
say
that so I'm assuming that you guys will
finish the other way around okay so what
is otherwise is when L Pi V of s is less
than L Pi U of
S okay so greater than less than so I'm
just assuming you guys will do that
right putting these things together
gives us
what
right
so what can infer from
this pointwise it's being drawn
closer right by gamma so the max
difference would also have come down
pointwise is being drawn closer even if
the max difference is at different
points right it should have
shrunk right so essentially that's it so
this essentially means that implies that
LP is the
contraction okay so next thing to do is
to start the same thing for the
optimality
equation right so we'll do that in the
next
class and then I have to also talk about
how do
you see I'm assuming that at every
point right at every point the functions
are being drawn
closer what that what
BR so I'm saying that L Pi vs minus L Pi
us is
closer right than the max difference
that you had in V minus
U right and this holds for all states
yes
right and
that's uh yeah right right hand side is
infinity n left hand side is just
absolute
value okay yeah so we also have to
show uh algorithms for solving this
right and uh so we'll do all of that in
the next class possibly it might spill
over into the subsequent class as well
[Music]
[Applause]